David McNeil St. Louis, Missouri - github.com/davidMcneil (314) 308-1596 - mcneil.david2@gmail.com

Profile

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for distilling requirements into real business problems and effective solutions. I develop solutions by drawing from my experience and embracing new languages and technologies. My programming language of choice is Rust for its efficiency and reliability, but I have experience with a wide range of technologies: Go, C++, TypeScript, React, WebAssembly, and embedded systems.

Experience

2019 - Now $Two\ Years$

Chef Software - Software Engineer - Remote - github.com/habitat-sh/habitat

- Core maintainer of Habitat an open source tool for packaging, distributing, and running applications.
- Migrated the codebase to async/await and Tokio a Rust asynchronous runtime.

TECHNOLOGY: Rust, NATS messaging system, Gossip protocols, Asynchronous runtimes

2016 - 2019 Three Years

n-ask Incorporated - Member of the Technical Staff - Aurora, Colorado

- Active Top Secret/Sensitive Compartmented Information (TS/SCI) clearance. - Designed, developed, and maintained a distributed system which ingests terabytes of data a day, processed

by DSP and geolocation algorithms, producing millions of results. Several web clients are used for system management and a native client is used extensively by analysts.

- Developed a canvas-based JavaScript mapping library for efficiently rendering millions of features.

TECHNOLOGY: C, C++, Docker, Go, InfluxDB, Java, Nomad, MongoDB, Python, Qt, React, Rust, TypeScript

2014 - 2015 $Three\ Months$ Indesign, LLC - Firmware Engineer Intern - Indianapolis, Indiana

Developed an embedded system which interfaced with numerous sensors and actuators.

TECHNOLOGY: C, Current Sensor, Hall Effect Sensor, MSP430, RFID Tags, Servo Motor

2014 - 2015Nine Months

Naval Surface Warfare Center - Senior Design Project - Crane, Indiana

Designed and developed a system to predict location based on RF spectrum data.

TECHNOLOGY: GPS, Python, Software Defined Radio, SQLite

2013 - 2014 Three Months Garmin Ltd. - Low Level Software Engineer Intern - Olathe, Kansas

Developed software for operating system profiling during route execution.

TECHNOLOGY: C, C++, Hardware Debugger

2012 - 2013

Cetani - Software Development Intern - Carmel, Indiana

Three Months

Developed a server for pushing real-time hospital notifications to front-end user interfaces.

TECHNOLOGY: C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Rails, Ruby, SQLServer

2011 - 2012

Oasis Digital - Software Development Intern - Chesterfield, Missouri

 $Three\ months$

Designed a work management system with a Node.js backend and responsive front-end.

TECHNOLOGY: Backbone.js, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL

Projects

2019

NATS Rust Client - github.com/davidMcneil/rants

A full-featured, asynchronous client for the NATS messaging system.

Technology: Rust, NATS messaging system

2017

The Rusty Web - github.com/davidMcneil/the-rusty-web

- One of the first complete resources detailing how to integrate Rust, compiled to asm. js or WebAssembly, into
- Benchmarked various implementations of the k-means clustering algorithm in different browsers.

Technology: asm.js, JavaScript, Rust, WebAssembly

2015 - 2016 One Year

Master's Thesis

Developed a RISC architecture with assembler, compiler, and simulator capable of adding custom instructions for doing performance analysis of tradeoffs between hardware and software implementations.

TECHNOLOGY: Bison, C++, Flex, LLVM

2015 - 2016

Machine Learning

Thirty Weeks Developed an image classifier, optical character recognition software, resistor classifier, voice recognition software, and completed the Machine Learning certification program from Stanford University.

TECHNOLOGY: MATLAB/Octave, Neural Networks, Python, Support Vector Machines, TensorFlow, Torch

Education

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology - Terre Haute, Indiana

2015 - 2016 One Year

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering with a focus on computer architecture.

2012 - 2015

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology - Terre Haute, Indiana

Three Years

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, Minor in Computer Science.

September 9, 2020